Hello, everyone. Welcome to this week's topic. This week, we're going to be talking about AI-assisted
theorem proving. So, in the last four weeks, we discussed really the fundamentals of theorem
proving, and I tried to make you practice and try for yourself how to do theorem proving manually
yourself without AI. So, in the first week, we studied the fundamentals, what is functional,
what is the syntax of functional programming in Isabelle, and then we studied some of the basic
proof methodologies and methods like mathematical induction and generalizing mathematical induction
hypothesis and case analysis and so forth. And then in the third week, we did recursion
on lists, but also on other more interesting structures like trees.
And we also discussed proof automation, basic proof automation in Isabelle. And then in the
fourth week, sorry, we didn't do trees in the third week, we did it all in the fourth week.
And then in the fourth week, we did algebraic datatypes, including trees and similar types and
doing induction on those datatypes. So, today, I will be introducing you to the last
most recent and most recent, as in like the most relevant and stated are part of the foundations
of the theorem proving, which is AI-assisted theorem proving. I will cover two types of AI-assisted
theorem proving. The first one is classical machine learning-based approaches, because
in fact, it's not LLMs that were only used for theorem proving. There were also
more applications of the standard approach to machine learning approaches like regression
and so forth. And these were from the early 2010s. And then we will talk about more modern
machine learning-based approaches like LLMs and modern reinforcement learning-based approaches.
But I wanted to say that, in general, this week's topic is, I want to say two points about
it before I move on. And it is very state-of-the-art. So, the visual, like I will not be able to cover
everything in the video, and I cannot record everything, because simply by the time I'm
recording, by the time I finish the recording, by the time I finish the recording, or by the
time you listen to this recording, it might be the case that the state of the art has
completely changed. So, what I will be doing is I will record some basics and then put some
papers for you to read. And these papers, I will try to reflect the state of the art
in those papers. So, I will put them all on the papers. All right, so...